Rhydian Jenkins

- in LinkedIn.com/in/rhydian-jenkins-30309085
- GitHub.com/RhydianJenkins
- **** 07384 629 336
- Rhydz@msn.com
- **♀** SA11 2LS

Personal Profile

Committed and driven Computer Science PhD graduate with an understanding of a variety of software and computing aspects. Experienced with working in groups and alone using a wide range of technologies including TS (Vue, Next, and Svelte), MVC Frameworks (Symfony/Zend/Laminas), Docker, and Java applications.

Passionate about learning, and familiar working in Windows and Linux environments, Containers, Virtual Machines and shells. Strives for a principle first approach when learning, combined with a passion to engage in any challenge with a 'can-do' attitude.

Skills

- Infrastructure and DevOps (Docker, Kubernetes, Git, GCP)
- Front end Vue, Next, Svelte
- Back end Symfony/Zend/Laminas MVC
- Package managment and build tools (npm, Composer, Docker-compose, Maven)
- Public speaking while presenting work at various conferences

History

WCBS

Full Stack Developer

Jan 2021–present Part of an agile team working remotely to develop a cloud native school Management Information System (MIS) solution, delivering frequent (2x weekly) releases on high standard product requirements. Operated using a broad tech stack, including Vue, Symfony, Redis, Kubernetes, Docker, and GitHub.

Responsibilities:

- Develop a Vue.js app in TS and JS
- Develop a RESTful API in Symfony
- Ensuring code quality through Jest/PHPUnit tests and code review
- Deploying releases through the various environments
- CI/CD through GitHub and Jenkins
- DevOps through the GCP, Kubernetes, and Docker
- Database and entity managment through Doctrine ORM

Aberystwyth University

2017-2021

University Tutor

Tutored Computer Science university students in a variety of different computer science contexts.

Responsibilities:

- Running workshops, lectures, and tuition groups with undergraduate students
- Hosting advisory sessions to help students through a wide range of problems
- One-to-one teaching
- Grading and supplying feedback to assignments and coursework

$\begin{array}{c} \textbf{Lexis Nexis} \\ \textbf{Risk} \end{array}$

Solutions May - Dec 2016

PHP Software Engineer

Operated with a team of developers/testers to implement industry quality software through a Zend Framework. Responsible for pushing code to a Jenkins CI server, and ensuring code quality through custom codesniffers and unit/integration tests.

Responsibilities:

- Working in an Agile team delivering user stories through sprints
- Peer reviewing code
- Developing features involving both front-end and back-end aspects
- Writing PHPUnit tests

Education

Aberystwyth University 2017–2021

PhD Topological Mapping Swarm Robotics

Worked on novel solutions for the topological multi-agent SLAM problem, using a swarm of agents to map out an environment.

Responsibilities:

- Developing a simulator for robotic operations
- Innovating novel ideas to solve challenging problems
- Communicating technical work for both short term and long term reports
- Self managing time and effort

Aberystwyth University 2014–2016

BSc Computer Science

During the degree, a wide range of technologies were studied which are still utilised today.

Modules:

- Web programming
- Java, C, and C++ programming paradigms
- Software development lifecycle
- \bullet Human computer interface and human computer interaction
- Agile methodologies
- Advanced computer graphics
- ullet Ubiquitous computing
- Space robotics
- Professional issues in the computing industry

NPTC College

A Levels

2012–2014

Computing, Computer Graphics, and Electrical Engineering.

Personal Details

- Enthusiast that enjoys experimenting with new and emerging technologies with a keen interested eye on the future of the industry.
- Experience with using ROS to control robots in simulation and real world application.
- Interests include rugby, personal fitness, and video games.
- Friendly and approachable personality, with confidence to ask questions and collaborate with others.
- Full UK driving licence.